wvu.edu 2019-06-13

# Privacy Notice | West Virginia University

West Virginia University (“University”) is dedicated to protecting individual privacy in accordance with our [Information Privacy Policy](https://it.wvu.edu/policies-and-procedures/privacy/information-privacy-policy). The University seeks to limit the collection and distribution of personal data to that which reasonably serves its academic, research, outreach, and administrative functions.

This privacy notice provides you with information on how the University collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through activities such as registering for a newsletter, requesting information or purchasing a product or service. 

It is important that you read this notice so that you are aware of how and why the University is using your personal information, which may be used independently or in combination to identify you.

## What Data This Website Collects

The University will not obtain your personal information when you visit www.wvu.edu, or any site within the wvu.edu domain, without your expressed consent. There may be sites within the wvu.edu domain that request personal information via forms. In these instances, the University will specifically request your consent to collect your data. If you choose not to provide personal data, the University may not be able to process your request.

Using Google Analytics (“GA”), the University does collect limited data from visitors to our website, such as geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system. This data is used to better understand how people find and use our webpages; however, none of this information personally identifies you to the University. GA also records your IP address which could be used to identify you but Google does not grant the University access to this data. GA also makes use of cookies; however, disabling cookies on your browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within a wvu.edu website. 

## How the University Uses Your Personal Information

The University will only use your personal data for legitimate business need. Should you choose to contact us and consent to providing us your data, none of the data that you supply will be stored by the website. That said, the data that you provide may be imported into mail services used for marketing purposes. You can request removal from any mailing list by using the unsubscribe link within all email messages sent by the University.

We use [CleanSlate CMS](https://cleanslatecms.wvu.edu/) to manage our website content. The data for CleanSlate is stored with Amazon Web Services.

## Third Party Processors

We use several third parties to process personal data on our behalf and include:

## Third Party Links

The www.wvu.edu website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties outside of the University to collect or share data about you. The University does not control these websites, plug-ins, and applications and is not responsible for their privacy policies. When you leave the University’s website, you are encouraged to read the privacy notice of every website or other link you visit.

## Data Security

The University has put in place [policies](https://it.wvu.edu/policies-and-procedures/security) and procedures to deal with suspected data security breaches. The University will notify you of any suspected data breaches in accordance with the law. Access to your personal data will be limited to those University employees who have a legitimate business need. 

The University will only retain your data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. After this period, your data will be securely destroyed in accordance with the University’s [Record Retention Policy and Schedule](https://generalcounsel.wvu.edu/record-retention-policy-schedule).

## Your Rights

You have a right to access and obtain a copy of your data and request us to change any incorrect or incomplete data. You can also request the University to delete or stop processing your data. The University will review all such requests and will remove identifying personal data that we do not have a legal or institutional obligation to maintain. Questions, concerns, and requests to delete personal information can be directed to the University’s Data Protection Officer:

Alex Jalso  
Information Security Services  
Information Technology Services  
One Waterfront Place  
Morgantown, WV 26506  
304-293-4457

## Changes to Privacy Statement

This privacy statement be revised to remain in line with changing legislation, technology or industry standards. The University will not explicitly inform our website users of these changes. Instead, it is recommended that you check this page for updates. Changes to the Information Privacy Policy will be noted in the revision history section of the policy.

Last Updated: January 4, 2019
